

Chicago, IL, USA

🛮 616.706.3471 | 💌 jim.kloet@gmail.com | 🖸 jimtheflash | 🛅 jimkloet | 💆 @jimkloet

## Summary\_

My goal is to help others make better decisions today and to equip them with the tools to make better decisions in the future. I am a proven leader of analytics and data science teams with organizations in e-commerce, CPGs, healthcare, insurance, SaaS, and research. I'm skilled at deploying machine learning and artificial intelligence tools, and teaching others how to do so as well.

## **Experience**

## **Slam Dunk Betting Services**

Chicago, IL, USA

HEAD OF PRODUCT & DATA SCIENCE, CO-FOUNDER

2024 - Present

- · We use machine learning to predict outcomes in NBA games and artificial intelligence to identify the best plays
- We developed real-time scraping tools to grab the latest odds from sportsbooks to feed our ML and AI tools

Reverb Chicago, IL, USA

MANAGER, Product Analytics & Data Science

2021 - 2024

- I built a team of 7 data scientists and analysts supporting data science and analytics needs for product and eng teams, and senior leadership
- We developed and supported tooling for running and analyzing 120-150 controlled A/B tests per year
- · We built and supported tools for gear recommendations, price predictions, and matching listings to entries in a music gear database

**ABC Supply Co.** Chicago, IL, USA

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST, IT Data Science

2019 - 2021

- · Led data science initiatives across several domains, including workforce management, associate retention, security, and e-comm
- Developed project plans and supervise students and interns on capstone projects and hackathons with university partners
- · Created and disseminated standards and best practices in data visualization and code management with R packages

Chicago, IL, USA

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST, Data Science as a Service

- · Developed containerized pipelines to ETL data to and from AWS environments using python for a CPG client
- · Generated recommendations for optimal nationwide pricing and promotion strategies, delivered via Tableau dashboard

Mattersight Chicago, IL, USA

DIRECTOR OF INSIGHTS & ANALYTICS, SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

2015 - 2019

2019 - 2019

- · Led team of data scientists and analysts responsible for reporting and ad-hoc analysis for all subscription clients
- Automated analytic tools in R and SQL to scale implementation of best practices in statistical analyses and data visualization
- Led presentations for clients and internal audiences on development and use cases for predictive analytics, esp. predictive CX measures

**RotoViz** 

DIRECTOR OF VISUAL APPLICATIONS, CONTRIBUTING WRITER

2013 - 2019

- · Develop web applications to give users insights into performance of professional sports teams and players
- Train new writers and developers in data science and data visualization methods using R

**Northwestern University** Evanston, IL, USA

TRANSLATIONAL RESEARCH FELLOW, DOCTORAL CANDIDATE, RESEARCH TECHNICIAN, Communication Sciences & Disorders

2009 - 2015

- Designed, executed, and analyzed experiments to investigate language and learning in the brain using fMRI and rTMS
- · Presented experimental results at conferences, invited lectures, and in peer-reviewed publications

Skills

**Programming** R, Python, SQL, dbt, html, css, ET<sub>F</sub>X

**Cloud & Distributed Computing Analytics & Business Intelligence**  Google Cloud, Azure, DataBricks, AWS, Hadoop

shiny, plotly, Tableau, Looker, PowerBI

## **Education**

**Northwestern University** 

Evanston, IL, USA

MA, PHD (ALL BUT DISSERTATION), Cognitive Science, Communication Sciences & Disorders

2006

**University of Michigan** 

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

BA, Psychology

JIM KLOET RESUME MAY 6, 2024